I believe in America.
America has made my fortune.
And I raised my daughter
in the American fashion.
I gave her freedom, but I taught her
never to dishonor her family.
She found a boyfriend, not an Italian.
She went to the movies with him.
She stayed out late.
I didn't protest.
Two months ago he took her for a drive
with another boyfriend.
They made her drink whiskey
and then they tried to
take advantage of her.
She resisted, she kept her honor.
So they beat her like an animal.
When I went to the hospital,
her nose was broken,
her jaw was shattered,
held together by wire.
She couldn't even weep
because of the pain.
But I wept. Why did I weep?
She was the light of my life.
Beautiful girl.
Now she will never be beautiful again.
Sorry.
I went to the police,
like a good American.
These two boys were brought to trial.
The judge sentenced them to three years
in prison, but suspended the sentence.
Suspended the sentence!
They went free that very day!
I stood in the courtroom like a fool.
Those two bastards, they smiled at me.
Then I said to my wife, "For justice,
we must go to Don Corleone."
Why did you go to the police?
Why didn't you come to me first?
What do you want of me? Tell me
anything, but do what I beg you to do.
What is that?
I want them dead.
That I cannot do.
I'll give you anything you ask.
I've known you many years, but this
is the first time you've asked for help.
I can't remember the last time
you invited me for a cup of coffee.
Even though my wife is godmother
to your only child.
But let's be frank here.
You never wanted my friendship.
And you were afraid to be in my debt.
I didn't want to get into trouble.
I understand.
You found Paradise in America.
You made a good living, had police
protection and there were courts of law.
You didn't need a friend like me.
But now you come to me and say,
"Don Corleone, give me justice."
But you don't ask with respect.
You don't offer friendship. You don't
even think to call me Godfather.
You come on my daughter's wedding
day and ask me to murder for money.
I ask you for justice.
That is not justice.
Your daughter is alive.
Let them suffer, then, as she suffers.
How much shall I pay you?
Bonasera, Bonasera.
What have I ever done to make you
treat me so disrespectfully?
If you'd come in friendship,
the scum that ruined your daughter
would be suffering this very day.
And if an honest man like you should
make enemies, they'd be my enemies.
And then they would fear you.
Be my friend?
Godfather?
Good.
Some day, and that day may never
come, I'll ask a service of you.
But until that day...
...accept this justice as a gift
on my daughter's wedding day.
- Grazie, Godfather.
- Prego.
Give this to Clemenza.
I want people that aren't going to
get carried away.
We're not murderers,
in spite of what this undertaker says.
- Where's Michael?
- Don't worry, he'll be here.
We're not taking the picture
without Michael.
- What's the matter?
- It's Michael.
Don Barzini.
Hey, Paulie! Let me have some wine.
Paulie! More wine.
- You look terrific on the floor.
- Are you a dance judge or something?
Take a walk around the
neighborhood, do your job.
Sandra, watch the kids.
Don't let them run wild.
You watch yourself, all right?
20, 30 grand. In small bills, cash.
In that little silk purse.
If this were somebody else's wedding...
Sfortunato!
Hey, Paulie!
Stupid jerk!
What's the matter?
- Have to go back to work.
- Tom.
Part of the wedding.
No Sicilian can refuse any request
on his daughter's wedding day.
Don Corleone, I'm honored and grateful
that you have invited me to your home.
Get out of here!
It's a private party. Go on!
What is it? It's my sister's wedding.
Goddamn FBI don't respect nothing!
Come here, come here, come here!
...but towards the end, he was paroled
to help with the American war effort,
so for six months he's worked
in my pastry shop.
Nazorine, what can I do for you?
Now that the war is over,
this boy, Enzo, they want to
repatriate him back to Italy.
Godfather, I have a daughter.
You see, she and Enzo...
You want Enzo to stay in this country,
and your daughter to be married.
You understand everything.
Mr Hagen. Thank you.
Wait till you see the wedding cake
I made for your daughter!
The bride, the groom and the angel...
- Who should I give this job to?
- Not to our paisá.
Give it to a Jew Congressman
in another district.
Who else is on the list?
Hey, Michael!
He's not on the list,
but Luca Brasi wants to see you.
Is this necessary?
He didn't expect to be invited to the
wedding, so he wanted to thank you.
Don Corleone, I'm honored and grateful
that you have invited me to your home
on the wedding day of your daughter.
May their first child be a masculine child.
Michael...
That man over there
is talking to himself.
See that scary guy over there?
- He's a very scary guy.
- What's his name?
His name is Luca Brasi.
He helps my father out sometimes.
Michael, he's coming over here!
You look terrific!
My brother Tom Hagen,
Miss Kay Adams.
Your father's been asking for you.
- Very nice to meet you.
- Nice to meet you.
If he's your brother why does
he have a different name?
My brother Sonny found
Tom Hagen in the street.
He had no home,
so my father took him in.
He's been with us ever since.
He's a good lawyer.
Not a Sicilian. I think he's
going to be consigliere.
- What's that?
- That's a...
...like a counselor, an advisor.
Very important for the family.
You like your lasagna?
Don Corleone.
I'm honored and grateful
that you have invited me
to your daughter's wedding.
On the day of your daughter's wedding.
And I hope that their first child
will be a masculine child.
I pledge my ever-ending loyalty.
- For your daughter's bridal purse.
- Thank you, Luca. Most valued friend.
Don Corleone, I'm going to leave you
now, because I know you're busy.
Thank you.
Signora Corleone!
No!
Senator Cauley apologized for not
coming, but said you'd understand.
Also some of the judges.
They've all sent gifts.
What is that outside?
Johnny! Johnny!
I love you!
He came all the way from California.
I told you he'd come!
- He's probably in trouble again.
- He's a good godson.
Johnny, Johnny! Sing a song!
You never said you knew
Johnny Fontane!
- Sure. You want to meet him?
- Great! Sure.
- My father helped him with his career.
- He did?
How?
- Let's listen to this song.
- Michael...
Please, Michael. Tell me.
When Johnny was starting out, he was
signed to a personal service contract
with a big bandleader.
And as his career got better and better,
he wanted to get out of it.
Johnny is my father's godson.
My father went to see this bandleader.
He offered him 10,000 dollars
to let Johnny go,
but the bandleader said no.
So the next day my father went to see
him, but this time with Luca Brasi.
Within an hour,
he signed a release
for a certified check of 1,000 dollars.
- How did he do that?
- Made him an offer he couldn't refuse.
- What was that?
- Luca Brasi held a gun to his head,
and father said that either his brains or
his signature would be on the contract.
That's a true story.
That's my family, Kay. It's not me.
Beautiful!
I'll take care of it.
Tom...
I want you to find Santino.
Tell him to come to the office.
How are you, Fredo?
My brother Fredo,
this is Kay Adams.
- Hi.
- How are you doing?
- This is my brother Mike.
- Are you having a good time?
Yeah. This is your friend?
I don't know what to do.
My voice is weak. It's weak.
Anyway, if I had this part in the picture,
it puts me right back on top again.
But this... man won't give it to me,
the head of the studio.
- What's his name?
- Woltz.
He won't give it to me,
and he says there's no chance.
No chance.
Sonny?
- Sonny, are you in there?
- What?
The old man wants you.
One minute.
A month ago he bought the movie rights
to this book, a best-seller.
The main character
is a guy just like me.
I wouldn't even have to act.
Godfather, I don't know what to do.
You can act like a man!
What's the matter with you?
Is this how you turned out a Hollywood
finocchio, that cries like a woman?
"What can I do?
What can I do?"
What is that nonsense?
Ridiculous.
- You spend time with your family?
- Sure I do.
Good.
Because a man who doesn't spend time
with his family can never be a real man.
You look terrible. I want you to eat.
Rest, and in a month this Hollywood
big shot will give you what you want.
It's too late, they start shooting
in a week.
I'm going to make him an offer
he can't refuse.
Just go outside and enjoy yourself,
and forget about all this nonsense.
- I want you to leave it all to me.
- All right.
- What time does my daughter leave?
- Soon, after they cut the cake.
Do we give your son-in-law
something important?
Never. Give him a living, but never
discuss the family business with him.
- What else?
- Virgil Sollozzo called.
- We'll have to see him next week.
- When you come back from California.
- When am I going to California?
- I want you to go tonight.
I want you to talk to this movie big shot
and settle this business for Johnny.
If there's nothing else, I'd like to go
to my daughter's wedding.
Carlo, we're going to take the picture.
Wait a minute.
No, Michael. Not me.
Okay, that's it. Just like that. Hold it!
- You need a little more heat on that arc.
- Start talking.
I was sent by a friend
of Johnny Fontane.
This friend would give
his friendship to Mr Woltz,
if Mr Woltz would grant us a favour.
Woltz is listening.
Give Johnny the part in that new
war film you're starting next week.
And what favour would your friend
grant Mr Woltz?
He could make your future union
problems disappear.
And one of your stars has just moved
from marijuana to heroin.
Are you trying to muscle me?
Listen, you son-of-a-bitch!
Let me lay it on the line. Johnny
Fontane will never get that movie!
No matter how many Dago Guinea
greaseballs come out of the woodwork!
- I'm German-Irish.
- Listen here, my Kraut-Mick friend.
- I'm going to make trouble for you!
- I'm a lawyer. I have not threatened...
I know almost every
big lawyer in New York.
Who the hell are you?
I have a special practice.
I handle one client.
Now you have my number,
I'll wait for your call.
By the way, I admire your pictures
very much.
Check him out.
- It's really beautiful.
- Look at this.
It used to decorate
the palace of a king.
Very nice.
Why didn't you say
you work for Corleone?
I thought you were some cheap hustler
Johnny was running in.
- I only use his name when necessary.
- How's your drink?
- Fine.
- Now I'll show you something beautiful.
You do appreciate beauty, don't you?
There you are.
$600,000 on four hooves.
I'll bet Russian czars never
paid that for a single horse.
Khartoum.
I'm not going to race him, though.
I'm going to put him out to stud.
Thanks, Tony.
Let's get something to eat.
Corleone is Johnny's godfather.
To the Italian people that's
a very sacred, close relationship.
I respect it. Tell him to ask me anything
else. This favour I can't give him.
He never asks a second favour
when he's been refused the first.
You don't understand. Johnny Fontane
never gets that movie.
That part is perfect for him.
It'll make him a big star.
I'm going to run him out of the business,
and let me tell you why.
Johnny Fontane ruined one of Woltz
International's most valuable protégés.
We trained her for five years.
Singing, acting, dancing lessons.
I spent hundreds of thousands of dollars
on her, I was gonna make her a big star.
Let me be even more frank.
To show you that I'm not a hard-hearted
man. That it's not all dollars and cents.
She was beautiful.
She was young and innocent!
She's the greatest piece of ass I've had
and I've had them all over the world.
Then Johnny Fontane comes along with
his olive oil voice and Guinea charm.
And she runs off.
She threw it all away
just to make me look ridiculous!
And a man in my position can't afford
to be made to look ridiculous!
Now you get the hell out of here!
If that goombah tries any rough stuff,
tell him I'm no bandleader.
Yeah, I heard that story.
Thank you for dinner
and a very pleasant evening.
Maybe your car can take me
to the airport.
Mr Corleone insists on hearing
bad news immediately.
- You're not too tired, are you, Tom?
- No, I slept on the plane.
I have the Sollozzo notes here.
Now...
Sollozzo is known as The Turk. He's
supposed to be very good with a knife,
but only in matters of business
with reasonable complaint.
His business is narcotics.
He has fields in Turkey,
where they grow poppy.
In Sicily he has plants to process them
into heroin.
He needs cash, he needs protection
from the police.
He'll give a piece of the action.
I don't know how much.
The Tattaglia family is behind him here.
They have to be in it for something.
- What about his prison record?
- One term in Italy, one here.
He's known as a top narcotics man.
- Santino, what do you think?
- A lot of money in that white powder.
Tom?
Yes. There's more money in narcotics
than anything else.
If we don't get into it, somebody else
will, maybe the five families.
With that money they can buy
more police and political power.
Then they come after us.
Now we have unions and gambling, and
that's great, but narcotics is the future.
If we don't get a piece of that action,
we risk everything in ten years' time.
So? What's your answer
going to be, Pop?
Don Corleone.
I need a man who has powerful friends.
I need a million dollars in cash.
I need those politicians that you carry
in your pocket, like nickels and dimes.
- What is the interest for my family?
- 30 per cent.
In the first year your end should be
three, four million dollars.
And then it would go up.
And what is the interest
for the Tattaglia family?
My compliments.
I'll take care of them, out of my share.
So I receive 30 per cent for finance,
political influence and legal protection?
That's right.
Why do you come to me?
Why do I deserve this generosity?
If you consider a million
dollars in cash just finance,
ti saluto, Don Corleone.
I said that I would see you, because
I heard you were a serious man,
to be treated with respect.
But, I must say no to you.
And I'll give you my reason.
It's true, I have a lot of friends in politics.
They wouldn't be friendly long if I was
involved in drugs instead of gambling,
which they regard as a harmless vice,
but drugs is a dirty business.
It doesn't make any difference to me
what a man does for a living.
But your business is...
a little dangerous.
If you're worried about security,
the Tattaglias will guarantee it.
- The Tattaglias would guarantee our...
- Wait a minute.
I have a sentimental weakness
for my children, and I spoil them.
They talk when they should listen.
But anyway...
Signor Sollozzo, my no is final. I wish to
congratulate you on your new business.
I know you'll do well, and good luck.
Especially since your interests
don't conflict with mine. Thank you.
Santino.
Come here.
What's the matter with you? Your brain
is going soft from playing with that girl.
Never tell anybody outside the family
what you're thinking again.
Go on.
Tom, what's this nonsense?
It's from Johnny.
He's starring in that new film.
- Take it away.
- Take it over there.
And...
...tell Luca Brasi to come in.
I'm a little worried
about this Sollozzo fellow.
Find out what he's got
under his fingernails.
Go to the Tattaglias.
Make them think that you're not
too happy with our family
and find out what you can.
I got something for your
mother and for Sonny
and a tie for Freddy, and
Tom Hagen got the Reynolds pen.
- What do you want for Christmas?
- Just you.
Andiamo, Fredo.
- Tell Paulie to get the car.
- Okay, Pop.
I'll have to get it myself.
Paulie called in sick this morning.
Paulie's a good kid.
I don't mind getting the car.
Buon Natale, caro. Grazie.
- Luca! I'm Bruno Tattaglia.
- I know.
You know who I am?
Tom! Tom Hagen. Merry Christmas.
- Glad to see you. I want to talk to you.
- I haven't got time.
Make time, Consigliere. Get in the car.
What are you worried about? If I wanted
to kill you, you'd be dead already.
Get in.
- Fredo, I'm going to buy some fruit.
- Okay, Pop.
Merry Christmas. I want some fruit.
Would you like me better
if I were a nun? Like in the story.
No.
- What if I were Ingrid Bergman?
- Now, that's a thought.
Michael.
No, I wouldn't like you better if you were
Ingrid Bergman. What's the matter?
They don't say if he's dead or alive.
- Sonny, it's Michael.
- Where have you been?
- Is he all right?
- We don't know yet.
There are all kinds of stories.
He was hit bad, Mikey.
- Are you there?
- Yeah, I'm here.
- Where have you been? I was worried.
- Didn't Tom tell you I called?
No. Look, come home, kid.
You should be with Mama, you hear?
Oh, my God.
Sonny!
Stay back there.
- Who is it?
- Open up, it's Clemenza.
There's more news about your old man.
Word is out that he's already dead.
- What's the matter with you?
- Take it easy!
- Where was Paulie?
- Sick. He's been sick all winter.
- How often?
- Only three, four times.
- Freddy didn't want a new bodyguard.
- Pick him up now.
I don't care how sick he is. Bring him
to my father's house right now.
- You want anyone sent over here?
- No. Go ahead.
I'm going to have a couple of our people
come over to the house.
- Hello?
- Santino Corleone?
- Yeah.
- We have Tom Hagen.
In three hours he'll be released
with our proposition.
Listen to what he has to say
before you do anything.
What's done is done. Don't lose that
famous temper of yours, Sonny.
I'll wait.
Your boss is dead.
I know you're not in the muscle end
of the family, so don't be scared.
I want you to help the Corleones
and me.
We got him outside his office
about an hour after we picked you up.
Drink it.
It's up to you to make peace
between me and Sonny.
Sonny was hot for my deal, wasn't he?
And you knew
it was the right thing to do.
- Sonny will come after you.
- That will be his first reaction, sure.
So you have to talk sense into him.
The Tattaglia family is behind me.
The other New York families will go
along with anything to prevent war.
Let's face it, with all due respect,
the Don - rest in peace - was slipping.
Ten years ago,
could I have gotten to him?
Well, now he's dead, Tom,
and nothing can bring him back.
You've got to talk to Sonny, to the
Caporegimes, Tessio, fat Clemenza.
It's good business, Tom.
I'll try. But even Sonny won't be able
to call off Luca Brasi.
Yeah, well...
Let me worry about Luca.
You just talk to Sonny.
And the other two kids.
- I'll do my best.
- Good.
Now you can go.
I don't like violence, Tom.
I'm a businessman.
Blood is a big expense.
He's still alive.
They hit him with five shots,
and he's still alive!
That's bad luck for me, and bad luck
for you if you don't make that deal.
Your mother is at the hospital with
your father. Looks like he'll pull through.
It's a lot of bad blood. Sollozzo, Philip
Tattaglia, Bruno Tattaglia, Ramon...
- You gonna kill all those guys?
- Stay out of it.
If you get rid of Sollozzo,
everything falls into line.
What about Luca?
Sollozzo thinks he can control him.
If Luca sold out, we're in a lot of trouble.
- Has anyone been in touch with Luca?
- We've been trying all night.
- Hey, do me a favour...
- Luca never sleeps over with a broad.
Well, Tom, you're consigliere.
What do we do if the old man dies?
If we lose the old man, we lose the
political contacts and half our strength.
The other New York families might
support Sollozzo to avoid a long war.
This is almost 1946.
Nobody wants bloodshed anymore.
If your father dies...
...you make the deal.
- Easy to say. He's not your father.
- I'm as much a son as you or Mike.
What is it?
- Paulie, I told you to stay put.
- The guy at the gates has a package.
Tessio, go see what it is.
- Want me to hang around?
- Yeah, hang around. Are you all right?
- Yeah, I'm fine.
- There's food. Are you hungry?
- No.
- A drink? Brandy will sweat it out.
- Go ahead.
- That might be a good idea.
Take care of that son-of-a-bitch.
Paulie sold out the old man.
- Make that the first thing on your list.
- Understood.
Mickey, tomorrow, get some guys
and go to Luca's apartment.
Maybe we shouldn't get Mike
mixed up in this too directly.
Hanging around the house on
the phone would be a big help.
Try Luca again.
- What's this?
- A Sicilian message.
It means Luca Brasi
sleeps with the fishes.
- I'm going.
- When will you be home?
I don't know, probably late.
- Don't forget the cannoli!
- Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Rocco, sit on the other side.
You block the rear-view mirror.
Sonny's running wild. He wants
to go to mattresses already.
We have to find a spot on the
West Side. Try 309 West 43rd Street.
- Know a good spot on the West Side?
- I'll think about it.
Think while you're driving.
I want to hit New York this month.
Watch out for the kids
when you're backing out.
Paulie, go down 39th Street, pick up
18 mattresses and bring me the bill.
Yeah, all right.
Make sure they're clean, because
the guys will be there a long time.
- They're clean and exterminated.
- That's a bad word to use.
Exterminate! Watch out,
so we don't exterminate you!
Pull over. I've got to take a leak.
Leave the gun. Take the cannoli.
Hey, Mike! Hey, Mikey!
- Yeah.
- Phone call!
- Who is it?
- Some girl.
- Hello. Kay?
- How's your father?
He's going to make it.
I love you.
I love you!
- Michael?
- Yeah, I know.
- Tell me you love me.
- I can't talk.
Can't you say it?
I'll see you tonight.
Hey Mikey! Why didn't you tell
that nice girl you love her?
I love you with all my heart. If I don't
see you again soon, I'm going to die!
Come and learn something. You might
have to cook for 20 guys some day.
You start with a little oil,
then fry some garlic.
Throw in some tomatoes, tomato paste,
fry it and make sure it doesn't stick.
You get it to a boil, you shove in
all your sausage and meatballs.
Add a little bit of wine.
And a little bit of sugar. That's my trick.
Cut the crap. I have more important
things for you. How's Paulie?
You won't see him anymore.
- Where are you going?
- To the city.
- Send bodyguards with him.
- I'm going to the hospital...
He'll be all right. Sollozzo knows
he's a civilian.
- Be careful, huh?
- Yes, sir.
Send somebody with him anyway.
- I have to go.
- Can I go with you?
No, Kay. There will be detectives there,
people from the press.
I'll wait in the cab.
I don't want you to get involved.
When will I see you again?
Go back to New Hampshire, and I'll
call you at your parents' house.
- When will I see you again, Michael?
- I don't know.
What are you doing here?
You're not supposed to be here.
I'm Michael Corleone. This is my father.
There's nobody here.
What happened to the guards?
Your father had too many visitors.
They interfered with hospital service.
The police made them leave
about ten minutes ago.
Get me Long Beach 45620, please.
Nurse. Wait a minute. Stay here.
Sonny, I'm at the hospital.
I got here late, there's nobody here.
No Tessio's men, no detectives,
nobody. Papa's all alone.
- Don't panic.
- I won't panic.
I'm sorry, but you will have to leave.
We're going to move him to another
room. Can you disconnect the tubes?
- That's out of the question!
- Do you know my father?
Men are coming here to kill him.
Do you understand?
Help me, please.
- Who are you?
- I am Enzo, the baker.
- Remember me?
- Enzo.
You'd better go,
there's going to be trouble.
If there is trouble, I'll stay here to
help you. For your father.
Listen. Wait for me outside,
in front of the hospital, all right?
I'll be out in a minute.
Just lie here, Pop.
I'll take care of you now.
I'm with you now.
I'm with you.
Get rid of these. Come here.
Put your hand in your pocket, like you
have a gun. You'll be all right.
You did good.
I thought I got all you
Guinea hoods locked up!
What the hell are
you doing here?
- Why isn't anyone guarding my father?
- Why, you little punk!
Don't you tell me my business!
I pulled them off.
- Stay away from this hospital!
- Not until my father's room is guarded.
- Phil, take him in!
- The kid's clean, Captain.
- He's a war hero. He's never been...
- I said take him in!
- What's The Turk paying you?
- Take a hold of him. Stand him up.
Stand him up straight.
I'm the Corleone's attorney. These men
are hired to protect Vito Corleone.
They're licensed to carry firearms.
If you interfere, you'll have to appear
before the judge and show cause.
Let him go.
- What's with all the new faces?
- We'll need them now.
After the hospital thing, Sonny got mad.
We hit Bruno Tattaglia this morning.
Jesus Christ.
Looks like a fortress around here.
Tommasuccio! Hey... 100 buttonmen
on the street 24 hours a day.
That Turk shows one hair on his ass,
he's dead.
Mike, let me look at you.
You're beautiful, beautiful.
You're gorgeous.
The Turk wants to talk! Imagine
the nerve of the son-of-a-bitch.
- He wants a meeting today.
- What did he say?
What did he say... He wants us to send
Michael to hear the proposition.
He promises that the deal
is too good to refuse.
- And Bruno Tattaglia?
- That's part of the deal.
- He cancels out what they did to Father.
- We should listen to them.
No more! Not this time, Consigliere.
No more meetings, discussions,
or Sollozzo tricks.
I want Sollozzo, or we go to war...
- The other families...
- They hand me Sollozzo!
This is business, not personal!
- They shot my father...
- Even that was business, not personal.
Then business will have to suffer.
Do me a favour.
No more advice on how to
patch things up. Just help me win.
I found out about Captain McCluskey,
who broke Mike's jaw.
He's definitely on Sollozzo's payroll,
and for big money.
McCluskey has agreed to be
The Turk's bodyguard.
So when Sollozzo is being guarded,
he's invulnerable.
Nobody has ever gunned down
a New York police captain.
All the families would come after you.
The Corleone family would be outcasts!
Even the old man's political protection
would run for cover.
Do me a favour.
Take this into consideration.
All right, we'll wait.
We can't wait. We can't wait.
No matter what Sollozzo says,
he's going to kill Pop.
That's the key for him.
We've got to get Sollozzo.
- Mike is right.
- Let me ask you something.
What about this McCluskey?
What do we do with this cop?
They want to have a meeting
with me, right?
It will be me, McCluskey and Sollozzo.
Let's set the meeting.
Get our informers to find out
where it's going to be held.
We insist it's a public place.
A bar, a restaurant.
Some place where there are people,
so I feel safe.
They'll search me when I meet them,
right?
So I can't have a weapon on me.
But if Clemenza can figure out a way to
have a weapon planted there for me...
...then I'll kill them both.
Nice college boy. Didn't want to
get mixed up in the family business.
Now you want to shoot a police captain
because he slapped you?
This isn't like the army! You have to get
close and get their brains on your suit.
You're taking this very personal.
Tom, this is business
and he's taking it personal.
- Where does it say you can't kill a cop?
- Come on, Mikey...
I'm talking about a cop who's mixed
up in drugs, a dishonest cop.
A cop who got mixed up in the rackets
and got what was coming.
That's a terrific story. We have
newspaper people on the payroll, right?
- They might like a story like that.
- They might.
It's not personal, Sonny.
It's strictly business.
It's as cold as they come. Impossible to
trace, so you don't worry about prints.
I put a special tape on the trigger
and the butt. Try it.
Is the trigger too tight?
My ears!
I left it noisy, so it scares away any
pain-in-the-ass innocent bystanders.
You've shot them both.
Now what do you do?
- Sit down, finish my dinner.
- Don't fool around.
Let your hand drop to your side
and let the gun slip out.
Everybody will still think you've got it.
They'll stare at your face,
so walk out fast, but don't run.
Don't look anybody in the eye,
but don't look away either.
They'll be scared stiff,
so don't worry about nothing.
You know, you're
gonna turn out be all right.
You'll take a vacation,
nobody knows where,
and we're gonna catch the hell.
How bad do you think it will be?
Pretty goddamn bad.
Probably all the other families
will line up against us.
That's alright.
These things have to
happen every five, ten years.
Helps gets rid of the bad blood.
Been ten years since the last one.
You have to stop them at the beginning.
Like they should have
stopped Hitler in Munich,
They should've not letting
him get away with that.
They were just asking for big trouble.
You know, Mike, we were all proud
of you. Being a hero and all.
Your father too.
Nothing. Not a hint. Absolutely nothing.
Even Sollozzo's people don't know
where the meeting will be held.
How much time do we have?
They're going to pick you up outside
Jack Dempsey's in an hour and a half.
- We could put a tail on them.
- Sollozzo would lose our ass.
- What about the negotiator?
- He's playing pinochle with my men.
- He's happy. They're letting him win.
- Too risky. Maybe we should call it off.
The negotiator plays cards
until Mike is back safe.
- He could blast whoever is in the car.
- They'll expect that.
Sollozzo might not even be
in the car, Sonny!
I'll get it.
Louis' restaurant in the Bronx.
- Is it reliable?
- My man in McCluskey's precinct.
A police captain is on call 24 hours
a day. He'll be there between 8 and 10.
- Anybody know this joint?
- Sure, I do. It's perfect for us.
A small family place, good food.
Everyone minds his business. Perfect.
They've got an old-fashioned toilet.
You know, the box and the chain thing.
We might be able to tape the gun
behind it.
All right. Mike, you go to the restaurant,
you eat, talk for a while, you relax.
Make them relax.
Then you go to take a leak. No, better
still, you ask permission to go.
Then you come back blasting.
Two shots in the head apiece.
I want somebody very good
to plant that gun.
I don't want him coming out
with just his dick in his hand.
- The gun will be there.
- You drive him and pick him up after.
Come on, let's move.
Did he tell you to drop the gun
right away?
Yeah, a million times.
Don't forget. Two shots apiece in
the head as soon as you come out.
How long do you think it will be
before I can come back?
At least a year.
I'll square it with Mom, that you're not
seeing her before you leave and...
I'll get a message to that girlfriend
when the time is right.
Take care.
Take care, Mike.
I'm glad you came. I hope we can
straighten everything out.
It's not the way I wanted things to go.
It should never have happened.
I want to straighten everything out.
I don't want my father bothered again.
I swear on my children
that he won't be, Mike.
But you have to keep an open mind
when we talk.
I hope you're not a hothead like Sonny.
You can't talk business with him.
He's a good kid.
I'm sorry about the other night, Mike.
I've got to frisk you, so turn around.
On your knees, facing me.
I guess I'm getting too old for my job.
Too grouchy.
Can't stand the aggravation.
You know how it is.
He's clean.
Going to Jersey?
Maybe.
Nice work, Lou.
- How's the food in this restaurant?
- Try the veal. It's the best in the city.
I'll have it.
- I'm going to speak Italian to Mikey.
- Go ahead.
What I want...
What's most important to me...
...is that I have a guarantee.
No more attempts on my father's life.
What guarantees can I give you?
I'm the hunted one!
I missed my chance.
You think too much of me, kid.
I'm not that clever.
All I want is a truce.
I have to go to the bathroom.
Is it all right?
When you got to go, you got to go.
I frisked him. He's clean.
Don't take too long.
I've frisked a thousand punks.
Okay, you take over.
I love you, Grandpa.
I'm sorry, Pa. He doesn't know you yet.
- Hey, big guy. Give it to Grandpa.
- Okay.
"I hope you get well, Grandpa, and wish
I see you soon. Your grandson Frank."
Go with your mother.
Take them downstairs.
Go on, Carlo, you too.
Go on.
- What's the matter with you, Carlo?
- Shut up and set the table.
Since McCluskey's killing, the police
have cracked down on our operations.
And also the other families.
There's been a lot of bad blood.
They hit us, so we hit them back.
Through our newspaper contacts
we've been able to put out material
about McCluskey's link with Sollozzo
in the drug rackets.
So things are loosening up.
And I sent Fredo to Las Vegas, under
the protection of Don Francesco of L.A.
- I want him to rest.
- I'm going to learn the casino business.
Where's Michael?
It was Michael who killed Sollozzo.
But he's safe. We're starting to work
to bring him back.
Did you find out where that old pimp
Tattaglia is hiding? I want him now.
Sonny, things are starting to loosen up.
If you go after Tattaglia, all hell
will break loose. Pop can negotiate.
- He must get better first. I'll decide...
- War is costly. We can't do business.
- Neither can they. Don't worry about it!
- We can't afford a stalemate.
- No more stalemate. I'll kill the bastard!
- You're getting a great reputation!
Do as I say! If I had a Sicilian wartime
consigliere, I wouldn't be in this shape!
Pop had Genco. Look what I got.
I'm sorry. I didn't mean that.
Ma made a little dinner. It's Sunday.
Niggers are having a good time
with our policy banks in Harlem.
Driving new Cadillacs,
paying 50 per cent on a bet.
That's because they've started
making big money.
Poppa never talked business
at the table.
- Shut up, Connie...
- Don't you ever tell her to shut up.
Don't interfere.
I'd like to talk to you after dinner.
I could do more for the family...
We don't discuss business at the table.
Hey, hey, take me to the America, G.I.!
Clark Gable!
America! Take me to the America, G.I.!
Clark Gable, Rita Hayworth!
I apologise if I offended you.
I'm a stranger in this country.
I meant no disrespect
to you or your daughter.
I'm an American, hiding in Sicily.
My name is Michael Corleone.
There are people who'd pay a lot
of money for that information.
But then your daughter
would lose a father...
...instead of gaining a husband.
I want to meet your daughter.
With your permission, and under
the supervision of your family.
With all respect.
Apollonia.
I'll knock you dizzy.
Save it for the library.
We've got to pick up my sister.
What's the matter?
- It was my fault!
- Where is he?
It was my fault. I hit him.
I started a fight with him.
I hit him, so he hit me...
I'm just going to get a doctor
to take a look at you.
Sonny, please don't do anything.
What's the matter with you?
What am I going to do?
Make that baby an orphan
before he's born?
You spic slobs still betting Yankees?
Tell them to stop taking in action.
We lost enough money last week.
Come here, come here!
If you touch my sister again,
I'll kill you.
Hey! We weren't expecting you,
Kay. You should call.
Yes, well I have. I mean,
I've tried writing and calling.
- I want to reach Michael.
- Nobody knows where he is.
We know that he's alright, but that's all.
- What was that?
- An accident, but nobody was hurt.
Tom, will you give this letter to Michael.
Please?
If I accepted that, a court could prove
I have knowledge of his whereabouts.
He'll get in touch with you.
I let my cab go, so can I call
another one, please?
Come on. Sorry.
- Hello?
- Is Carlo there?
- Who is this?
- A friend of Carlo.
Tell him that I can't make it tonight
until later.
Bitch!
- Dinner's on the table.
- I'm not hungry.
- The food is getting cold.
- I'll eat out later.
You just told me to make you dinner!
She has a filthy mouth, this Guinea brat.
That's it, break it all, you spoiled
Guinea brat. Break it all!
Why don't you bring your whore
home for dinner?
Maybe I will.
- Clean it up!
- Like hell I will!
You skinny, spoiled brat.
Clean it up! Clean it up!
Clean it up! I said, clean it up!
Clean it up!
Clean it up. Clean that up, you...
Clean it!
Clean it up! Yeah, kill me.
Be a murderer, like your father!
- All you Corleones are murderers!
- I hate you!
Come on, kill me!
Get out of here!
- I hate you!
- Now I'll kill you.
You Guinea brat. Get out of here!
Connie, what's the matter?
I can't hear you.
Connie, talk louder. The baby's crying.
Santino, I can't understand.
I don't know.
Yeah, Connie.
You wait there.
No, you just wait there.
Son-of-a-bitch.
- Son-of-a-bitch!
- What's the matter?
Open the goddamn gate!
Get off your ass.
Sonny!
- Sonny.
- Get out of here!
Go after him, go on!
Son-of-a-bitch. Come on!
Give me a drop.
My wife is crying upstairs.
I hear cars coming to the house.
Consigliere of mine,
I think you should tell your Don
what everyone seems to know.
I didn't tell Mama anything.
I was about to come up and wake you
and tell you.
But you needed a drink first.
Yeah.
Well, now you've had your drink.
They shot Sonny on the causeway.
He's dead.
I want no inquiries made.
I want no acts of vengeance.
I want you to arrange a meeting...
...with the heads of the five families.
This war stops now.
Call Bonasera.
I need him now.
This is Tom Hagen. I'm calling for
Vito Corleone, at his request.
You owe your Don a service.
He has no doubt that you will repay it.
He will be at your funeral parlor
in one hour. Be there to greet him.
Well, my friend, are you ready
to do me this service?
Yes. What do you want me to do?
I want you to use all your powers
and all your skills.
I don't want his mother
to see him this way.
Look how they massacred my boy.
What's wrong?
Are you driving yourself, Boss?
Is your wife coming with you?
No, take her to her father's house
until things are safe.
Okay, anything you say.
Fabrizio!
No, Apollonia!
Don Barzini, I want to thank you
for helping me organize this meeting,
and the other heads of the five families
from New York and New Jersey.
Carmine Cuneo from the Bronx,
and from Brooklyn...
...Philip Tattaglia.
And from Staten Island
we have with us Victor Strachi.
And the other associates that came as
far as from California and Kansas City
and all the other territories
of the country. Thank you.
How did things ever get so far?
I don't know.
It was so unfortunate, so unnecessary.
Tattaglia lost a son, and I lost a son.
We're quits. And if Tattaglia agrees,
then I'm willing to let things go on
as before.
We're grateful to Don Corleone
for calling this meeting.
We all know him as a man of his word.
A modest man who listens to reason.
Yes, Don Barzini. He's too modest.
He had all the judges and politicians
in his pocket.
He refused to share them.
When did I ever refuse
an accommodation?
All of you know me.
When did I ever refuse,
except one time? And why?
Because I believe this drug business
will destroy us in the years to come.
It's not like gambling or liquor
or even women,
which is something that most people
want, but is forbidden by the Church.
Even the police that have helped us in
the past with gambling and other things
will now refuse to help us
when it comes to narcotics.
I believed that then...
and I believe that now.
Times have changed.
It's not like the old days,
when we could do anything we wanted.
A refusal is not the act of a friend.
If Don Corleone had all the judges and
politicians, then he must share them
or let others use them. He must let us
draw the water from the well.
Certainly he can present a bill
for such services.
After all, we're not communists.
I also don't believe in drugs.
For years I paid my people extra, so
they wouldn't do that kind of business.
Somebody says to them
"I have powders."
"If you put up 3-4,000 dollar investment,
we can make 50,000 distributing."
They can't resist. I want to control it
as a business, keep it respectable.
I don't want it near schools,
I don't want it sold to children.
That's an infámia.
In my city we would keep the traffic
to the colored.
They're animals,
so let them lose their souls.
I hoped that we could come
here and reason together.
And I'm willing to do whatever is
necessary to find a peaceful solution.
We are agreed. The traffic in drugs
will be permitted, but controlled.
Don Corleone will give us protection
in the east, and there will be peace.
I must have strict assurance
from Corleone.
As time goes by and his position
becomes stronger,
will he attempt any individual vendetta?
We are all reasonable men.
We don't have to give assurances.
You talk about vengeance.
Will vengeance bring your son
back to you?
Or my boy to me?
I forgo the vengeance of my son.
But I have selfish reasons.
My youngest son was forced
to leave this country...
...because of this Sollozzo business.
And I have to make arrangements
to bring him back here safely.
Cleared of all these false charges.
But I'm a superstitious man.
If an unlucky accident should befall him,
if he should be shot by a police officer,
or if he should hang himself
in his jail cell,
or if he's struck by a bolt of lightning,
then I'm going to blame
some of the people in this room.
And that I do not forgive.
But, that aside...
...let me say that I swear...
...on the souls of my grandchildren,
that I will not be the one to break
the peace we've made here today.
Should I insist that all of Tattaglia's
drug middlemen have clean records?
Mention it. Don't insist.
- Barzini will know without being told.
- You mean Tattaglia.
Tattaglia's a pimp. He could never
have outfought Santino.
But I didn't know until this day
that it was Barzini all along.
Come on, Nancy.
Keep together, everyone. Brian.
Okay, all right.
How long have you been back?
I've been back a year.
Longer than that, I think.
It's good to see you, Kay.
I'm working for my father now, Kay.
He's been sick. Very sick.
But you're not like him. You told me you
weren't going to become like your father.
My father is no different
than any other powerful man.
Any man who's responsible
for other people.
Like a senator or president.
- You know how naive you sound?
- Why?
They don't have men killed.
Who's being naive, Kay?
My father's way of doing things is over.
Even he knows that.
In five years the Corleone family
is going to be completely legitimate.
Trust me. That's all I can tell you
about my business. Kay...
Michael, why did you come here? Why?
What do you want with me after all
this time? I've been calling and writing.
I came because I need you.
I care for you.
- Please stop it, Michael.
- Because... I want you to marry me.
- It's too late.
- Please, Kay...
I'll do anything you ask to make up for
what's happened to us.
Because that's important, Kay.
Because what's important is that...
...we have each other.
That we have a life together.
That we have children. Our children.
Kay, I need you.
And I love you.
Barzini's people chisel my territory
and we do nothing about it!
- Soon I'll have no place to hang my hat!
- Be patient.
I'm not asking for help.
Just take off the handcuffs.
- Be patient.
- We've got to protect ourselves.
- Let me recruit some new men.
- No.
I don't want to give Barzini
an excuse to start fighting.
Mike, you're wrong.
Don Corleone...
You once said that one day Tessio
and me could form our own family.
Till today I would never think of it.
I must ask your permission.
Michael is now head of the family.
If he gives his permission,
then you have my blessing.
After we make the move to Nevada
you can take off from the Corleone
family and go on your own.
After we make the move to Nevada.
- How long will that be?
- Six months.
Forgive me, but with you gone, me and
Pete will come under Barzini's thumb.
I hate that Barzini. In six months' time
there will be nothing left to build on.
- Do you have faith in my judgment?
- Yes.
- Do I have your loyalty?
- Always, Godfather.
Then be a friend to Michael.
Do as he says.
Things are negotiated that'll solve your
problems and answer your questions.
That's all I can tell you now.
Carlo, you grew up in Nevada.
When we make our move there,
you'll be my right-hand man.
Tom Hagen is no longer consigliere.
He'll be our lawyer in Vegas.
That's no reflection on Tom,
just how I want it.
If I ever need help, who's a better
consigliere than my father?
That's it.
- Thank you, Poppa.
- I'm happy for you, Carlo.
Mike... Why am I out?
You're not a wartime consigliere, Tom.
Things may get rough with the move.
Tom.
I advised Michael. I never thought
you were a bad consigliere.
I thought Santino was a
bad Don, rest in peace.
Michael has all my confidence,
just as you do.
But there are reasons why you must
have no part in what is going to happen.
- Maybe I could help.
- You're out, Tom.
I can't get over the way your face looks.
So good!
This doctor did some job.
Did Kay talk you into it?
Hey, hey, hey, hey!
Hey, wait, hey!
Leave them out here.
He's tired and wants to clean up.
Let me open the door, all right?
- Hello, Mike! Welcome to Las Vegas!
- All for you, kid! It's all his idea.
- Your brother Freddy.
- Girls?
I'll be right back. Keep them occupied.
- Anything you want, kid, anything.
- Who are the girls?
- That's for you to find out.
- Get rid of them, Fredo.
- Hey, Mike...
- I'm here on business. Get rid of them.
I'm tired. Get rid of the band too.
Hey, take off. Take off. Let's go.
Hey, that's it. Hey, Angelo.
Hey, come on! Scram!
Come on, honey. I don't know
what's the matter with him, Johnny.
Sorry.
I don't know. He's tired.
What happened to Moe Greene?
He had some business. He said to
give him a call when the party started.
Well, give him a call.
- Johnny, how are you?
- Nice to see you, Mike.
- We're proud of you.
- Thanks.
Sit down, I want to talk to you.
The Don is proud too.
Well, I owe it all to him.
He knows how grateful you are.
That's why...
he'd like to ask a favour of you.
Mike, what can I do?
We're thinking of giving up our interests
in the olive oil business and settle here.
Now Moe Green will sell us his share
of the casino and the hotel,
so it can be completely
owned by family. Tom!
Mike, are you sure about that?
Moe loves the business. He never
said nothing to me about selling.
I'll make him an offer he can't refuse.
See, Johnny...
See, we figure that entertainment
will be a big factor
in drawing gamblers to the casino.
We hope you'll sign a contract
to appear five times a year.
Perhaps convince some of your friends
in the movies to do the same.
We're counting on you.
Sure, Mike.
I'll do anything for my godfather.
You know that.
Good.
Hey, Mike! Hello, fellows.
Everybody's here. Freddy, Tom.
- Good to see you.
- How are you, Moe?
Have everything? Specially prepared
food, the best dancers, and good credit.
Draw chips for everybody,
so they can play on the house.
Is my credit good enough
to buy you out?
Buy me out?
The casino, the hotel. The
Corleone family wants to buy you out.
The Corleone family
wants to buy me out?
No, I buy you out.
You don't buy me out.
Your casino loses money.
We can do better.
- You think I'm skimming off the top?
- You're unlucky.
You goddamn Guineas
really make me laugh.
I do you a favor and take Freddy here in
when you're having a bad time,
and now you try to push me out!
You took Freddy in because the Corleone
family bankrolled your casino
because the Molinari family honor
code guaranteed his safety.
Now let's talk business.
Yes, let's talk business, Mike.
First of all, you're all done.
The Corleone family don't even
have that kind of muscle anymore.
The Godfather is sick, right?
You're getting chased out of New York
by Barzini and the other famillies.
What do you think is going on here?
You think you can come to
my hotel and take over?
I talked to Barzini. I can make a deal
with him and still keep my hotel!
Is that why you slapped my brother
around in public?
That was nothing, Mike.
Moe didn't mean nothing by that.
He flies off the
handle once in awhile,
but Moe and me are good friends.
Right, Moe, huh?
I've got a business to run.
I've got to kick asses
sometimes to make it run right.
We had a little argument, Freddy and I,
so I had to straighten him out.
You straightened my brother out?
He was banging cocktail
waitresses, two at a time!
Players couldn't get
a drink at the table.
What's wrong with you?
I leave for New York tomorrow.
Think about a price.
Son-of-a-bitch!
Do you know who I am?
I'm Moe Greene!
I made my bones when you
were out with cheerleaders.
Wait a minute, Moe. I have an idea.
Tom, you're the consigliere.
Talk to the Don...
Just a minute. Don is semi-retired and
Mike is in charge of the family business.
If you have anything to say,
say it to Michael.
Mike, you don't come to Las Vegas and
talk to a man like Moe Greene like that!
Fredo...
You're my older brother, and I love you.
But don't ever take sides with
anyone against the family again.
I have to see my father and his people,
so have dinner without me.
This weekend we'll go out.
We'll go to the city, we'll see a show,
and we'll have dinner.
Oh, Michael. Your sister wants
to ask you something.
- Let her ask.
- She's afraid to.
They want you to be godfather
to their boy.
- We'll see.
- Will you?
Let me think about it. Come on.
Barzini will move against you first.
He'll set up a meeting with someone
you absolutely trust.
Guaranteeing your safety.
And at that meeting
you'll be assassinated.
I like to drink wine more than I used to.
Anyway, I'm drinking more.
It's good for you, Pop.
I don't know.
Your wife and children,
Are you happy with them?
- Very happy.
- That's good.
I hope you don't mind the way I keep
going over this Barzini business.
No, not at all.
It's an old habit.
I spend my life trying not to be careless.
Women and children can
be careless, but not men.
- How's your boy?
- He's good.
You know he looks more
like you every day.
He's smarter than I am.
He's three years old and can
read the funny papers.
Read the funny papers.
I want you to arrange for a telephone
man to check all in- and out-going calls.
I did it already.
I took care of that, Pop.
That's right. I forgot.
What's the matter?
What's bothering you?
I'll handle it.
I told you I can handle it,
so I'll handle it.
I knew that Santino would
have to go through all this.
And Fredo...
Fredo was, well...
But I never wanted this for you.
I worked my whole life.
I don't have to apologise for
taking care of my family.
And I refused to be a fool,
dancing on a string held
by all those big shots.
I don't apologise. That's my life,
but I thought that...
that when it was your time, that...
that you would be the one
to hold the strings.
Senator Corleone.
Governor Corleone. Something.
Another pezzo da novanta.
Well...
Just wasn't enough time, Michael.
Wasn't enough time.
We'll get there, Pop. We'll get there.
Now listen, whoever comes to you
with this Barzini meeting,
he's the traitor. Don't forget that.
Can I hold it, please?
- Can I water these?
- Yes, go ahead.
Over here, over here.
Be careful. You're spilling it.
Antony!
Come here, come here.
That's it. We'll put it right there.
I'll show you something. Come here.
Stand there.
Give me an orange!
That's a new trick.
You run in there. Run in there.
Where are you?
Mike, can I have a minute?
Barzini wants to arrange a meeting.
He says we can straighten out
any of our problems.
- You talked to him?
- Yeah.
I can arrange security. On my territory.
- All right?
- All right.
Do you know how they're
going to come at you?
They're arranging a
meeting in Brooklyn.
Tessio's ground.
Where I'll be safe.
I always thought it would be
Clemenza, not Tessio.
It's the smart move.
Tessio was always smarter.
But I'm going to wait.
After the baptism.
I've decided to be godfather
to Connie's baby.
And then I'll meet with Don Barzini
and Tattaglia.
All the heads of the five families.
Michael, do you believe in God,
the Father Almighty,
Creator of Heaven and Earth?
I do.
Do you believe in Jesus Christ,
His only Son, our Lord?
I do.
Do you believe in the Holy Ghost,
the Holy Catholic Church?
I do.
Michael Francis Rizzi,
do you renounce Satan?
I do renounce him.
And all his works?
I do renounce them.
Oh, God!
- And all his pomps?
- I do renounce them.
Michael Rizzi,
will you be baptized?
I will.
Michael Rizzi, go in peace, and may
the Lord be with you. Amen.
Kay!
Kiss your godfather.
Carlo. I can't go to Vegas.
Something's come up.
Everybody has to leave without us.
- Mike, it's our first vacation!
- Connie, please.
Go back to the house, wait for my call.
It's important.
I'll only be a couple of days.
We're on our way to Brooklyn.
- I hope Mike can get us a good deal.
- I'm sure he will.
Sal, Tom, the boss says he'll come in a
separate car, so you two go on ahead.
- That screws up my arrangements.
- That's what he said.
I can't go either, Sal.
Tell Mike it was only business.
I always liked him.
- He understands that.
- Excuse me, Sal.
Tom, can you get me off the hook?
- For old times' sake?
- Can't do it, Sally.
You have to answer for Santino, Carlo.
- Mike, you got it all wrong.
- You fingered Sonny for Barzini.
That little farce you played
with my sister.
You think that could
fool a Corleone?
I'm innocent. I swear on the kids.
- Please, don't do this.
- Sit down.
Don't do this to me, please.
Barzini is dead.
So is Philip Tattaglia.
Moe Greene.
Strachi. Cuneo.
Today I settle all family business,
so don't tell me you're innocent, Carlo.
Admit what you did.
Get him a drink.
Come on.
Don't be afraid, Carlo.
Come on, do you think I'd
make my sister a widow?
I'm godfather to your son, Carlo.
Go ahead, drink, drink.
No, you're out of the family business.
That's your punishment.
You're finished.
I'm putting you on a plane to Vegas.
Tom.
I want you to stay there. Understand?
Only don't tell me you're innocent.
Because it insults my intelligence.
Makes me very angry.
Who approached you?
Tattaglia or Barzini?
It was Barzini.
Good.
There's a car waiting outside
to take you to the airport.
I'll call your wife and tell her
what flight you're on.
- Mike...
- Get out of my sight.
Hello, Carlo.
- I'm trying to tell you...
- Mama, please!
Michael!
- What is it?
- Where is he?
Michael, you lousy bastard!
You killed my husband.
You waited until Papa died,
so nobody could stop you.
You blamed him for Sonny.
You always did, everybody did.
But you never thought about me!
Now what are we going to do?
Connie.
Why do you think he kept
Carlo at the Mall?
All the time, he knew
he was going to kill him.
And you stood
godfather to our baby.
You lousy cold-hearted bastard!
Want to know how many men he had
killed with Carlo? Read the papers!
That's your husband,
that's your husband!
No! No, no...
Take her upstairs. Get her a doctor.
She's hysterical.
Hysterical.
Michael, is it true?
- Don't ask me about my business, Kay.
- Is it true?
Don't ask me about my business.
Enough!
All right.
This one time.
This one time I'll let you
ask me about my affairs.
Is it true?
Is it?
No.
I guess we both need a drink.
Come on.
Don Corleone.